After that,
（岡部倫太郎(おかべりんたろう)）それから俺は…
in order to save Mayuri,
まゆりを助けるために…
I time-leaped over and over.
何度もタイムリープをした
しかし…
But...
どんな手を尽くしても―
no matter what I did,
まゆりは…
Mayuri...
死んだ
...died.
Even if Moeka and SERN never attacked,
（岡部）
萌郁(もえか)たちの襲撃がなくても
it was like fate itself kept murdering her.
運命に殺されるように…
It was like the entire world
まるで 世界が結託して―
まゆりを
殺そうとしているかのように
was conspiring to kill her.
（アナウンサー）この影響により…
（椎名(しいな)まゆり）はあー
（岡部）
さっきから 全く動いていない！
The cars aren't moving!
（運転手）
電車が止まっているからねえ
The train's stopped.
（岡部）急いでください！
裏道でも何でもいいから
Hurry!
Take a back road or something!
（運転手）
そう言われても… フーッ
That's not really an option, sir.
（まゆり）あれ？
まゆしぃの懐中 止まっちゃってる
Huh? Mayushii's watch isn't working.
（まゆり）おかしいなあ
（岡部）あっ…
That's strange.
（まゆり）
さっきネジ巻いたばっかりなのに
I just wound it.
Again...
（岡部）まただ… まただ！
Again!
（岡部）まゆり！
Mayuri!
（運転手の悲鳴）
（岡部）んんっ
Shiina Mayuri was the one who died.
（桐生(きりゅう)萌郁）
死んだのは椎名まゆりです
岡部君… いえ
岡部倫太郎は逃走しました
Okabe...
I mean, Okabe Rintarou has escaped.
No matter what I do,
（岡部）何をどうしようが
no matter what I try,
どんな方法を取ろうが
死んでしまう
she dies.
It's like fate...
これじゃあ まるで運命じゃないか
そうか これこそ…
I see. So this is...
そんなものはない！
There's nothing like that!
機関もシュタインズ･ゲートも―
The Organization... Steins Gate...
and fate!
運命の選択も！
They don't exist!
そんなもの… ない！
Physically
Necrosis
（牧瀬紅莉栖(まきせくりす)）
どういうこと？ 説明してよ！
～
What do you mean?
Explain!
（橋田 至(はしだいたる)）
個別ルート確定したところだお
せめてセーブだけでも…
I just got to the individual character route.
At least let me save—
俺がやっておく
I'll do it.
Just get out of Akihabara.
とにかく 秋葉原(あきはばら)から離れるんだ
いいな？
Got it?
岡部？ あっ…
Okabe...
あっ
（岡部の震える息）
ああ…
（紅莉栖）あっ
Mayuri just left.
（岡部）
まゆりは もう出たあとか…
It's exactly the same.
同じだ
No matter how many times I try to save her,
いくら まゆりを逃がそうとしても
結局は…
in the end...
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Even the message is the same.
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
（岡部）
メールまで同じ　メール…
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
The message.
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
Assistant
Did something
happen?
Tell me later, okay?
"Shining Finger."
（岡部）シャイニング･フィンガー
タイムマシンの新たな情報が
手に入った
"I have new information regarding the time machine."
"I'd like to talk to you alone."
２人だけで話がしたい
（岡部）
動くな　両手を挙げろ
Don't move.
Put your hands up.
（岡部）お前たちの正体は？
Who are you people?!
（岡部の荒い息）
Part-time job.
（萌郁）
バイト　アークリライトの…
Arc rewrite.
I know you're planning to attack the lab and kidnap us!
（岡部）
お前たちが今晩 ラボを襲い―
俺たちを誘拐しようと
していることは分かっている
How?
（萌郁）なぜ？
（岡部）俺が未来から来たからだ！
Because I've come from the future!
分かったか？ 早く答えろ！
Do you understand?
Now answer me!
My phone...
（萌郁）メールで…
（岡部）ダメだ！ 早く答えろ！
No!
Answer me now!
お前たちはＳＥＲＮ(セルン)なのか？
Are you with SERN?
Rounder.
（萌郁）ラウンダー
（岡部）ラウンダー？
Rounder?
任務はＩＢＮ5100の回収
Our mission is to recover the IBN 5100.
So you're the one who stole it!
あれを盗んだのも お前なのか？
I don't know anything.
（萌郁）知らない
（岡部）とぼけるな！
Don't fuck with me!
Ｄメールを送ったのが
きっかけで… あっ
You sent that D-mail...
I see.
（岡部）
そうか 世界線が変わって
The world line changed,
so she has no memory of sending that message.
Ｄメールを送った記憶は
今の萌郁にはない
なぜ ラボを襲う？
Why do you plan to attack the lab?
The IBN 5100 isn't there anymore.
ＩＢＮ5100は
あそこには もうないんだぞ！
Too late.
（萌郁）もう…
（岡部）答えろ！
Answer me!
理由は３つある
Three reasons.
One.
１つ　君たちは
知ってはいけないことを知った
You've learned something you shouldn't have.
Two.
２つ　タイムマシンを作り上げた
You made a time machine.
３つ　世間に公表しようとした
Three.
You wanted to publicly announce it.
そんなことまで…
You knew all that?
Does SERN know?
ＳＥＲＮも
そのことを知っているのか？
My orders come from FB.
私の指示はＦＢから来る
（岡部）
ＦＢ？ ＳＥＲＮの内部組織か？
FB?
Is that an organization within SER—
FB is everything to me.
（萌郁）ＦＢは私のすべて
Where am I?
（岡部）ここは？
Don't move.
（ラウンダー１）動くな
（岡部）ハッ
（萌郁）
君なの？ ジョン･タイターは
Are you John Titor?
（岡部）ハア…
（萌郁）考えられない　君しか
You're the only person he could be.
（岡部）ハッ… 違う
No!
あ…
Where am I?
（岡部）ここは…
The bomb threat has halted all the trains.
（ラウンダー２）脅迫電話によって
列車はすべてストップしています
According to plan.
予定どおりです
Capture Makise Kurisu and Hashida Itaru.
（萌郁）
牧瀬紅莉栖　橋田 至を確保
それ以外は必要ない
No one else is needed.
Wait!
まっ… うっ
ハア… 待ってくれ！ 頼む！
W-Wait!
Please don't kill Mayuri!
まゆりを…
まゆりを殺さないでくれ！
（岡部）謝る！ 俺が悪かった
I'm sorry!
I was wrong!
I never wanted to expose SERN!
別にＳＥＲＮの何かを
暴こうとしたわけじゃない！
タイムリープマシンは渡す
I'll give you the time leap machine!
知ったことは一切 口外しない
I'll never tell anyone what I learned!
（萌郁）状況開始
Begin the mission.
お願いだ 何でもする！
Please! I'll do anything!
Please... It was just simple curiosity...
お願いだ…
ただの好奇心だったんだ
遊びみたいなものだったんだ
It was a game!
だから まゆりだけは…
So... just spare Mayuri...
（萌郁）もう 遅い
It's too late.
あっ ああ… まゆり…
Mayuri...
まゆり… ああ…
あっ ああ…
まゆりー！
Mayuri!
（ラウンダー３）黙ってろ！
Shut up!
（岡部）うっ！ まゆり！
Mayuri!
Mayuri...
（岡部）まゆり…
くっ　ううっ…
（紅莉栖）んっ？
（岡部の荒い息遣い）
（紅莉栖）どうしたの？
What's wrong?
Were you napping?
もしかして 居眠りでもしてた？
This again...
（岡部）またそれか…
（紅莉栖）えっ？
（岡部）もう…
（紅莉栖）あっ
I can't take this anymore!
（岡部）たくさんだ！
（紅莉栖）岡部！
Okabe!
（橋田）なんぞ？
What's wrong?
You don't need to destroy it.
何も壊さなくても…
We decided we aren't doing the time leap.
タイムリープしないって
決めたんでしょ？
（岡部）はっ…
（紅莉栖）どうしたの？ 急に
What's gotten into you?
You're going shopping for the party, right?
買い出し行くんでしょ？
パーティーの
（岡部）
ハッ… パーティーは… くっ
The party...
（紅莉栖）ちょっと 岡部！
Wait, Okabe!
（紅莉栖）ハッ…
（男の子）ガタンガタン　新幹線
It's the bullet train!
（母親）
違うでしょ 新幹線は白いの
No, the bullet train is white.
Oka—Kyouma...
（漆原(うるしばら)るか）
あっ 岡… うっ 凶真(きょうま)さん
Where's Mayuri?
（岡部）まゆりは？
Mayuri already left.
まゆりちゃんなら さっき…
I know.
（岡部）知ってる
（るか）えっ？
ここに
パーティーに誘いに来たことも
I know she came to invite you to the party...
and that she's going to meet her friend who cosplays...
コスプレ友達のために―
ラボに戻る前に
寄り道してくることも！
I know she's looking forward to the party.
あいつがパーティーを
楽しみにしていることも！
All of it!
全部！ うう…
あっ
I'm sorry.
すみません
（岡部）なのに… なのに俺は…
But...
But I...
What are you doing over there?
（紅莉栖）そんな所で何してる？
Kurisu.
紅莉栖…
初めて まともに名前を呼んだな
That's the first time you've ever called me by the real name.
What happened?
何があった？ いや 何が起きる？
No, what's going to happen?
あんた
タイムリープして来たんでしょ？
You time leaped, didn't you?
It's all my fault.
（岡部）すべて 俺の責任だ
岡部？
Okabe.
It's all my fault.
（岡部）全部 俺の責任なんだ
ダルにハッキングしろなんて
言わなければよかった
I never should've told Daru to hack into SERN.
タイムマシンを作ろうなんて
言わなければよかった…
I never should've said to make the time machine.
I never should've invited Moeka to be a lab member!
萌郁を
ラボメンにしなければよかった
It's my fault... and Mayuri...
俺のせいで まゆりは…
You're pushing yourself too hard, idiot.
（紅莉栖）無茶しやがって　バカ
We don't know if the time leap machine is completely safe.
タイムリープマシンは
絶対安全とは限らないのよ
It's possible you could completely erase yourself from existence.
場合によっては―
あんたの存在 そのものが
なくなる可能性だって
On a fundamental level, humans are temporal creatures.
“人間は根源的に
時間的存在である”
あっ ハイデガーね
私も今 それを言おうとしてた
Heidegger... I was just about to say that.
I learned that phrase from you.
お前から教わった言葉だ
That's kind of creepy.
（紅莉栖）なんか 気持ち悪いわね
頭の中をのぞかれてるみたいで
It's like you're peeking inside my head,
でも タイムリープって
いうのは―
but I guess that's what a time leap is.
そういうことなのかも
しれない
What should I do?
（岡部）俺は どうすればいい？
When will the lab be attacked?
ラボが襲われるのは何時？
After 7:30.
（岡部）７時半すぎだ
I can think of several possible causes for Mayuri's death,
（紅莉栖）まゆりが
どうして死んでしまうのか―
いくつか可能性は考えられる
でも 今は話してる時間はない
but we don't have time to talk.
Let's go.
行こう
まゆりは大切な仲間よ
私だって助けたい
Mayuri's a dear friend.
I want to save her too!
ハッ…
すまない
I'm sorry.
謝らないでよ
Don't apologize.
I want to help you.
力になりたいの　私が
I really do.
あっ
ほら
狂気のマッドサイエンティスト
Hey, mad scientist!
世界の構造とやらを
作り替えるんだろ？
You're going to change the world, right?
Of course!
無論だ！
フーハッハッハッハッ…
ウフッ…
でしょ？
Right?
ハッ
フフッ
（紅莉栖）
時間は今から５時間ほど前―
I set the time to five or so hours ago,
ちょうどタイムリープマシンが
完成するころにセットしておいた
right when the time leap machine was created.
If you go back before it's completed, it's possible I won't finish it.
完成前まで飛ぶと―
マシンが完成しなくなる可能性が
生まれるから
（まゆり）うーん
（紅莉栖）
あんたは そこへ飛んで―
So you go back in time,
and once the time leap machine is done,
タイムリープマシンが完成したら
みんなを解散させて―
send everyone away and tell me what we just discussed.
私に さっきの話をして
If you say you've come from the future,
未来から来たと言えば
多分 私は信じる
I'll probably believe you.
How can you be sure?
（岡部）なぜ 分かる？
I know myself better than anyone.
私のことは
私が一番よく知っている
I'm the one who made the time leap machine to begin with.
そもそも タイムリープマシンを
開発したのは私なのだぜ
あっ 自分のマシンに
自信があると言うことか？
You mean you're confident about your work?
まあね　さっき
岡部を見たときも確信してた
I guess so.
When I saw you back there, I was certain.
Certain that you had time leaped.
タイムリープして来たんだって
念のため
キーワードを決めておきましょうか
Just in case, let's decide on a keyword.
あっ
（紅莉栖）私が今 一番 欲しい物は
マイ フォークである
Right now, what I want most is
My Fork.
You want one?
欲しいのか？ マイ フォーク
A fork?
そう　マイ スプーンは
もう持ってるし
Yeah, I already have My Spoon.
…って そこに興味を持つな！
Don't be so nosy!
んっ 行くわよ
Here we go!
あっ ああ
Okay.
Five hours ago,
５時間前の私はさ…
I won't remember that you called me Kurisu...
知らないんだよね
あんたが
紅莉栖って呼んでくれたこと
あっ…
ウフッ
Do you think you could hold this?
（まゆり）これをね
持っててくれないかなー
Like this?
（岡部）こうか？
（まゆり）そうそう
That's right.
Keep it spread out like that!
そうやって
ビローンって広げたままね
（紅莉栖）ウフッ
へえー そのリボン カワイイわね
That ribbon's cute.
でしょ？
あっ 紅莉栖ちゃんも着てみる？
Isn't it?
Want to try it on?
I still have some cosplay outfits for Comima.
今度のコミマ まだコスあるよ
Cosplay, huh?
コスプレか
Interested?
（橋田）もしかして 興味あるん？
そっ そんなわけないでしょ！
N-No way!
（橋田）おう？
I couldn't wear that in public...
こんなの 人前で着るなんて
うん？
（岡部）
そうか ５時間前というと
まだ まゆりが出かける前
I see.
Five hours ago, Mayuri hadn't left.
たしか まゆりのコスが
完成すると同時に―
As I recall, her cosplay outfit and the time leap machine were completed at the same time.
タイムリープマシンも…
（紅莉栖）あっ
It's done!
（まゆり）出来た！
（紅莉栖）あっ
ジャーン　私の勝ちだね
競争してたんだ
I win!
We were racing.
アハッ やられた
I lose.
でも こっちも もう終わり
But we're almost done too.
これで完成
Now it's finished.
これが…
This is...
（岡部）実験はしない！
We won't do the experiment!
（紅莉栖･橋田）えっ？
（まゆり）あっ…
（岡部）
しまった いきなりすぎたか？
Damn... Was that too sudden?
どういうこと？
What do you mean?
あっ
Y-You're all tired.
み… みんな
疲れているだろうから 話はあとだ
We'll talk later.
We're done for today.
今日は これで解散とする
（紅莉栖）うん？
I'll take a plate.
（岡部）皿
（店員）お皿 １丁
One plate.
Why here?
なぜ ここなんだ？
ちょうど注文したら
あんたからのメールが来たのよ
I already ordered here when I got your message.
I didn't think you were a regular here.
まさか お前が
ここの常連とはな
べっ 別に常連ってわけじゃ
I-I'm not a regular!
Mayuri told me about this place.
まゆりに教えてもらったの
…で 話って何よ？
So what did you want to talk about?
You told us all to leave, and then
いきなり“解散”って
言ったかと思えば―
you suddenly texted me.
今度はメールなんかしてきて
You see...
実はな…
I've come from five hours in the future.
俺は５時間後の未来から来た
はっ？ 何 そのバカっぽいセリフ
What? That's the stupidest line I've ever heard.
（岡部）なっ…
お前 言ってることが
全然 違うじゃないか！
H-Hey! That isn't what you said!
You said you'd probably believe me!
何が“私は多分 信じる”だ
What are you talking about?
なーに 勝手に言いだしてる？
Probably believe you?
多分とか信じるとか
論理性皆無の発言―
I wouldn't say anything that illogical.
私がするわけないだろ
You did say it!
言ったんだ！
"I'm the one who made the time leap machine to begin with."
“そもそも タイムリープマシンを
作ったのは私なのだぜ”とか―
得意げに！
You looked really proud too!
アハッ バカじゃないの？
Are you a moron?
Well, whatever...
はいはい ワロス ワロス　うん…
I really want to smack her...
（岡部）この女 殴りたい…
あっ！
Right now, what you want most is...
お前が今 一番 欲しい物は
マイ フォークである
"My Fork".
（岡部）どうだ？
Well?
ホントに話したの？
５時間後の私が？
I really told you that?
The five-hours-from-now me?
You said you already had "My Spoon".
マイ スプーンは
もう持っているからともな
うっ… 恨むぞ ５時間後の私！
Screw you, future me...
これで俺を信じる気になっただろ？
You believe me now, right?
ハッ そうね
Yeah... So the machine works like I thought it would.
あのマシン やっぱり
理論どおり完璧なんだ
It's perfect.
フッ
（店員）お皿 お待ち
Here's your plate.
（阿万音鈴羽(あまねすずは)）んっ…
I see.
（紅莉栖）なるほどね
これが すべて事実なら
かなりヤバい状況ね
That sounds bad, if it's all true.
（岡部）ああ
Yeah.
Rather than help Mayuri escape, have you tried stopping Moeka...
まゆりを逃がすのではなく
萌郁さん… ラウンダーだっけ？
A Rounder, you called her?
How about stopping her and her group?
その連中を止めるというやり方は？
試した
I did.
だが 結局
まゆりの死は止められなかった
But I couldn't stop Mayuri's death.
I see.
そう…
For something to occur, it must have a cause.
ある物事が起きる“結果”には―
必ず それを引き起こす
“原因”が存在する
Cause
Death
Effect
Normally, death would be preceded
通常 死という結果の原因には
そこに至る直接的な事象―
by some proximate phenomenon
like an accident or an illness,
例えば 病気や事故なんかが
考えられるけど―
but we can't be sure about the cause.
それは 原因とは断言できない
The Rounders are the proximate cause of Mayuri's death,
まゆりを死に追いやっているのは
直接的にはラウンダーだけど―
恐らく本当の原因は違う
but the real cause is likely different.
So even if the Rounders never appear,
だから
ラウンダーが関わらなくても―
Mayuri still dies.
まゆりは死んでしまう
（岡部）なら 原因は何だ？
Then what's the cause?
Cause
Death
Effect
分からない
I don't know.
It's possible that the cause of Mayuri's death
もしかしたら “まゆりが
生まれたという原因”が―
is Mayuri's own birth.
“まゆりの死という結果”を
導いているのかもしれない
（岡部）寿命ということか？
You mean her life span runs out?
That's fatalism!
運命論じゃないか それは…
Indeed.
（紅莉栖）
ええ　だから私は支持しない
So I won't suggest it.
The cause should be something that initiated this series of events.
原因は この事件の引き金として
説明できるような事柄のはずよ
Initiated...
（岡部）引き金…
もしかして これが完成しなければ
まゆりは…
Is it possible that if this wasn't completed, Mayuri would...
Wait.
（紅莉栖）待って
短絡的に答えを出すのは危険よ
It's dangerous to jump to conclusions!
しかし…
But...
（鈴羽）
牧瀬紅莉栖の言うとおりだよ
Makise Kurisu is right.
（岡部･紅莉栖）あっ
あなた… 何か知ってるの？
You're...
Do you know something?
（鈴羽）
あんたの推理は大体 合ってる
You're more or less correct.
Fixing everything won't be as easy as not completing the time leap machine.
確かにタイムリープマシンが
なければ解決するなんて―
簡単なものじゃない
世界を救うには
たどり着かなきゃいけないんだ
To save the world,
you need to reach it.
Cross the 1% divergence barrier to the world line beta.
ダイバージェンス
１％の壁を越えて―
ベータ世界線に
（鈴羽）
ダイバージェンスというのは
The divergence number
indicates this world line's location.
この世界線が
どこにあるかを示す数値
And the only clue we have as to what it is,
その数値を指し示す
唯一の手がかりが―
このダイバージェンスメーター
is this divergence meter.
（岡部）ニキシー管とは
作ったやつは いい趣味をしている
Nixie tubes?
Whoever made it has good taste.
（鈴羽）そりゃそうだよ
作ったのは岡部倫太郎なんだから
Of course he does.
You're the one who made it.
（岡部）んっ！ 俺？
I did?
You have the power to retain
君は世界線を移動したとき―
your memories when moving world lines.
前の世界線の記憶を
持ち続ける力がある
（鈴羽）
それを利用して 未来の君が
In the future, you made this meter
前の世界線と今の世界線が
どれくらい違うのかを―
to numerically display the difference between this world line and the previous one you came from.
数値化するメーターを作ったんだ
0.337187...
（紅莉栖）0,337187？
（鈴羽）それが今の世界線
That's this world line.
世界線っていうのは―
A world line is like a woven braid or this rope.
ちょうど毛糸とか
このロープみたいなもんなんだ
ふんっ
This rope looks like it's a single line,
（鈴羽）
このロープは 一見１本だけど―
but actually, many thin threads comprise it.
実際には いくつもの細い糸が
集まって作られている
The threads are the world lines.
この糸が世界線
One never touches the others,
（鈴羽）１つ１つが
干渉し合うことはないけど
but they all go to the same place.
伝っていった先の
たどり着く結果は一緒なんだ
（紅莉栖）つまり すべてが
まゆりの死という結果に―
In other words,
they all move toward a world in which Mayuri dies?
向かってるってことか
（鈴羽）うん
でも 世界線が大きく変動して
今いるアルファ世界線から―
But if the world line drastically changes
from our alpha world line to the beta world line and over the 1% barrier,
１％を越えて
ベータ世界線へ移動すると―
別の結果となる
another outcome would occur.
You guys use that one.
さて 君たちは そっち使ってね
えっ 待ってよ
これだけで登るなんて無理よ
Wait.
I can't climb up with just that.
しょうがないなあ
Oh, fine...
Just wait here.
ここで待ってて
よいしょ うんっ んっ…
（２人）ああ…
（鈴羽）えいっ ふっ…
あっ 阿万音さんって…
Who is Amane, anyway?
She's definitely a professional of some kind.
確実にプロだな　何かの
（２人）あっ
ほら 行くよ　早く
Let's go.
Hurry.
The alpha and beta world lines
アルファ世界線とベータ世界線は
大幅に結果が…
are world lines with completely different results.
つまり 未来が異なる世界線
Normally, it's impossible to move between them.
本来 行き来することは
不可能なんだ
Even if you change the past using time leaps and D-mails,
Ｄメールやタイムリープで
過去改変を行っても―
移ることはできない
you can't do it.
But sometimes, major events occur,
ただし 世界に大きな事件が起きて
その選択によって―
and the choices made then split the world into multiple world lines.
未来が変わる世界線の
分岐点のような年が いくつかある
In recent history, it would be 1991 when the Gulf War occurred.
最近だと 湾岸戦争が起きた1991年
2000, with Y2K,
2000年問題があった2000年
そして
タイムマシンが開発された2010年
and 2010 with the creation of the first time machine.
これって…
This is...
（鈴羽）分岐が起きるときなら
アルファ世界線から―
When the split occurs,
it's possible to move from the alpha world line to the beta.
ベータ世界線への移動が
可能になるんだ
どうやって移動するんだ？
方法は？
How is it done?
How—
Wait!
待って
その前に あなたの正体を教えて
Before that,
tell us who you are.
（岡部）あ…
（紅莉栖）あっ
This is...
（岡部）これは…
（鈴羽）タイムマシン
a time machine.
（紅莉栖）あっ
私は2036年から来たんだ
I'm from the year 2036.
鈴羽…
Suzuha...
I am the time traveler...
私がタイムトラベラー
John Titor.
ジョン･タイターだよ
～